James T. Cox Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
James T. Cox Collection
1900 - 2003
NPKMC-223-159
30 linear feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
James T. Cox
The James T. Cox Collection consists of plays, both professional and amateur (student), musicals, and screenplays. Also included are several videotapes of the Marist College Council on Theatre Arts productions. The portion of the collection consisting of student written plays was developed by Gerard A. Cox.
Collection Overview
James Cox was a man of theatrical dreams. Although he never made it to stardom, he continued to live his dream by whatever means possible. The theatre became a principle role in his life beginning in grammar school and continued to be his life-long goal. Throughout his life, Jim Cox participated in several aspects of theatre, from acting, to directing, to working along the sides of the “techies." Jim also collected a life's worth of scripts and plays. His wish was to allow this collection to be made available for students to find their way to their own dreams.
The James T. Cox Collection consists of plays, both professional and amateur (student), musicals, and screenplays. Also included are several videotapes of the Marist College Council on Theatre Arts productions. The portion of the collection consisting of student written plays was developed by Gerard A. Cox.
The James T. Cox Collection was developed by both James T. Cox and Gerard A. Cox. The Cox collection was donated to the Marist College Library by Gerard A. Cox.
Historical Note
James Thomas Cox was a lifelong lover of theatre and its arts in all shapes and forms. He developed an "itch" for theatre while a child in elementary school where a woman by the name of Anna Day taught Jim and his peers elocution and directed them in a variety of stage presentations that were closer to vaudeville than to the theatre world of today. As a young man in high school he was recognized as an avid reader of play scripts who couldn't wait to direct and perform and consequently formed a theatre company while still in school. (One of the first members to join him was a classmate, Anna Maria Italiano, later to be recognized as the Oscar and Tony winning actress, Anne Bancroft.) An account of the highs and lows of the years of struggling "to make it in show biz" can be read in "Thank You, Jonas Bronck," an autobiography written with humor, sensitivity and compassion.
The story of James Thomas Cox is not spectacular, but it is a remarkable example of the countless stories of theatre practitioners who never become household names. His career in the theatre included roles performed on the stage and on radio and in television and movies. His roles most often were character roles played in the background as support for stars. He did this on the small screen in episodes of "Hill Street Blues," "Cagney and Lacey," "The Judge," and "Official Detective" among others. He performed on stages from New England to Texas to Maryland to California. He had roles in productions of "Excess Baggage," "Cold Storage," "The Happy Time," "Tobacco Road," "Deathtrap," "Clash By Night," "Two Old Farts Reading Shakespeare," and "Steambath."
Prior to his death he asked that his extensive collection of play scripts be made available to students and faculty. This special collection is the fulfillment of that request. Perhaps it will enable others in going after what they want most. Go for it, keeping in mind one of this man's favorite sayings: "The only ladder to the stars is woven with dreams."
There are no restrictions on this collection
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into four series: 1) Student Plays Written for Festival, has 20 subseries, 2) Student Plays, 3) Videos, and 4) Published Plays, Musicals, and Screenplays
Series are arranged chronologically, by subject, alpabetically by title, or by catalog entry
- Student Plays Written for Festival, 1989 - 2002; 1; Boxes: 1 - 7
  Chronological
  - Subseries 1.: Theatre Workshop, 1989; 1.1; Box: 1
    - We Are Companions On A Journey, O'Hara, John (Box 1)
    - A Bight to Eat, Meyer, Chris (Box 1)
    - It's A Dog's Life, Callahan, Elizabeth (Box 1)
    - An Ordinary Travel Through Time, Sabol, Richard K. (Box 1)
    - Without Humor, Meyer, Chris (Box 1)
    - Straight Up, Please, Lawless, Christina (Box 1)
    - The Game, Meyer, Chris (Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.2: Theatre Workshop: Festival '90 - Student Scripts, Volume I, 1990; 1.2; Box: 1
    - Death Meets the Lovebug, Higgins, Bob (Box 1)
    - The Honeymooners Get Divorced, Budd, Ed (Box 1)
    - Cars, Lecky, John (Box 1)
    - Piece of Mind, Glaze, Anndalena (Box 1)
    - The F Word, Liepis, Marc (Box 1)
    - Backstage, Miller, Mark (Box 1)
    - The Shark Tank, Liepic, Marc (Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.3: Theatre Workshop: Festival '90 - Student Scripts, Volume II, 1990; 1.3; Box: 1
    - Unsuspecting Customers, Dwyer, Kevin (Box 1)
    - Complications, O'Connor, Kerin (Box 1)
    - The Unsung Hero, Speers, Michael (Box 1)
    - Final Judgment, McEneney, Ed (Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.4: New Short Plays by Students, 1991; 1.4; Box: 1
    - Farewell Tour, Liepis, Marc (Box 1)
    - The Bridal Shower, O'Connor, Kerin (Box 1)
    - Known But To God, O'Hara, Jamie (Box 1)
    - Trashed, Wing, Terrence (Box 1)
    - Intimate Relations, Glaze, Anndalena (Box 1)
    - True Confessions, Cunney, Don (Box 1)
    - Life At Twenty, Roy, R.A. (Box 1)
    - Truth Game, Walker, Alicia (Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.5: New Short Plays by Students: 1992 (Spring Semester), 1.5; Box: 1
    - Madness To My Method, Liepis, Marc (Box 1)
    - The Porch Swing, Gaze, Anndalena (Box 1)
    - A Small Town Dream, Bryndle, Amy (Box 1)
    - The Final Destination, Gallup, Laura (Box 1)
    - Wagner's Temptation, Timpone, Peter (Box 1)
    - Oh and Please, Call Me Joe, Schatzle, Barbara K. (Box 1)
    - 2 Hearts, Joseph, Jim (Box 1)
    - Looking For Inspiration, Anson, Amy (Box 1)
    - Motherly Love, Barrott, Michelle (Box 1)
    - Going To The Chapel, Dooley, Christine (Box 1)
    - The Last Visit, Cerabone, Jon (Box 1)
    - Dance With Me, Liriano, A.Z. (Box 1)
    - Moonmist, Giaquinto, Matthew (Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.6: A Book of New Short Plays (Spring Semester), 1992; 1.6; Box: 2
    - 72nd Street Messiah, Budd, Ed (Box 2)
    - Dreamah, Roche, John (Box 2)
    - Cutting Remarks, Liepis, Marc (Box 2)
    - Shakes and Spears, Lake, Ronald (Box 2)
    - Not Me, Crary, Kami (Box 2)
    - Epiphany, Speers, Mike (Box 2)
    - Moonmist (Revised), Giaquinto, Matthew (Box 2)
    - Cyanide, Fieldman, Eugene (Box 2)
    - Duke of Prunes, Fieldman, Eugene (Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.7: New Short Plays by Students (Spring Semester), 1992; 1.7; Box: 2
    - The Card Shop, Sheeran, Christine (Box 2)
    - Check Please, Gretziner, Gerard M. Jr. (Box 2)
    - Charlie's Independence Day, Lynch, Jim (Box 2)
    - There's No Such Thing as Love in the World of the Blue-Headed Man, Albano, Matt (Box 2)
    - Dysfunctional, Iacono, Christopher W. (Box 2)
    - Blackout (a love story in the dark), Giaquinto, Matthew (Box 2)
    - Academy Avenue, Speers, Mike (Box 2)
    - Hanging By A Thread, Savitsky, Anne P. (Box 2)
    - From the Porch, Zurlo, Vinnie (Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.8: New Plays: Volume I (Spring 1993), 1.8; Box: 2
    - The Farther To Fall, Gretzinger, Gerard M. Jr. (Box 2)
    - Green Pastures, Ten Eyck, David (Box 2)
    - Bennie, Lindeman, Max (Box 2)
    - Red Tape For The Boa Constrictor, Iacono, Christopher W. (Box 2)
    - Family Affairs, Gretzinger, Gerard M. Jr. (Box 2)
    - Fool's Gold, Di Iorio, Stephanie (Box 2)
    - Second Chances, Gretzinger, Gerard M. Jr. (Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.9: New Plays: Volume II (Spring 1993), 1.9; Box: 3
    - The Dream-Maker, Jack, Deborah (Box 3)
    - Return to Forever, Haggerty, James (Box 3)
    - Sean Morgan's Family Solution, Budd, Ed (Box 3)
    - A Room With No View, Crary, Kami (Box 3)
    - Madison's Murder, Lake, Ronald (Box 3)
    - Truman, Haggerty, James (Box 3)
    - Jake's Ladder, Anderson, Jerome (Box 3)
    - One Fish, Two Fish, Galpin, Christian G. (Box 3)
    - Untitled, Crary, Kami (Box 3)
    - A Look At The View, Galpin, Christian (Box 3)
    - The Year the Real World Began, McGovern, Mary Ann (Box 3)
    - Worship Zylophone, Jack, Deborah (Box 3)
    - Kay's Prerogative, Crary, Kami (Box 3)
    - Red Tape For The Boa Constrictor (Revised), Iacono, Christopher W. (Box 3)
    - Not Me (Revised), Crary, Kami (Box 3)
  - Subseries 1.10: Theatre Workshop: Festival '94, 1994; 1.10; Box: 3
    - Escaping Reality, Altomare, Scott (Box 3)
    - A Modern Fairy Tail, Feick, Erica (Box 3)
    - Wiser Than My Years, Gonell, Louis (Box 3)
    - As Time Goes By, Gretzinger, Gerard M. Jr. (Box 3)
    - Scenes From An Italian Restaurant, Hadhazy, Andrea (Box 3)
    - The Further Adventures of Hamlet, Miller, Lou (Box 3)
    - What Would You Do If..., Naumann, Stephanie (Box 3)
    - All Screwed Up, Redecindo, Sagrario (Box 3)
    - Jack In The Box, Saraceno, Roseanne (Box 3)
    - Insult To Injury, Targos, Robert (Box 3)
  - Subseries 1.11: Student Written Plays Prepared for Festival '95, 1995; 1.11; Box: 3
    - One Last Game, Damiani, Christopher (Box 3)
    - Déjà Vu, Danis, Michael (Box 3)
    - My Life, Feick, Erica L. (Box 3)
    - The Possibility, Feick, Erica L. (Box 3)
    - Family Dinner, Hadhazy, Andrea (Box 3)
    - God Games, Landry, Karen (Box 3)
    - The Crèche on Main Street: The Nativity Scene, Murphy, Andrea (Box 3)
    - Suburbia Dreamin, Ryan, Sean (Box 3)
    - Going Up, Saraceno, Roseanne (Box 3)
    - The Hare and the Handicapped, Targos, Robert G. (Box 3)
  - Subseries 1.12: Student Written Plays Prepared for Festival '96 (Book I), 1996; 1.12; Box: 4
    - One Thousand and One Oranges, Cahill, Bryon (Box 4)
    - Why???, Clark, Patricia E. (Box 4)
    - Honest Exchange, Hadhazy, Andrea (Box 4)
    - Reality Check, Naumann, Stephanie (Box 4)
    - A Cracked Diamond, Patulak, Jennifer (Box 4)
    - The Wait, Tokash, Andrew (Box 4)
    - Blue, Tokash, Andreq (Box 4)
  - Subseries 1.13: Student Written Plays Prepared for Festival '96 (Book II), 1996; 1.13; Box: 4
    - A Knock At The Door, Cahill, Bryon (Box 4)
    - A Prisoner Of The Mind, Feick, Erica L. (Box 4)
    - The Underground, Landry, Karen (Box 4)
    - Tombstones, Saraceno, Roseanne (Box 4)
    - Honest Exchange (Revised), Hadhay, Andrea (Box 4)
  - Subseries 1.14: Stage One: Plays in Progress (Collection of Student Written Plays, 1997; 1.14; Box: 4
    - Of Brass Rings and Finer Things, Gallagher, Tom (Box 4)
    - Legend Had It, Landry, Karen (Box 4)
    - Armageddon Vs. Joe Shmoe, Cahill, Bryon (Box 4)
    - NIHL, McNamara, Shannon M. (Box 4)
    - Let's Talk About Sex, Tokash, Andrew (Box 4)
    - Something Like Believe, Cahill, Bryon (Box 4)
    - How Little They Know, White, Michelle Corrine (Box 4)
    - Premonition, Freydl, Jef. E. (Box 4)
    - The Paths of Progress, Ten Eyck, David (Box 4)
    - A Man in a Chair, A Woman at the Window, Fishelman, Ben (Box 4)
    - Brotherhood, Kennedy, Clifden (Box 4)
    - Mortimer Gets Some or Mortimer Bites the Big Apple, Murray, John& Linhart Paul (Box 4)
  - Subseries 1.15: As Grapes Upon the Vine: A Collection of New Plays, 1998; 1.15; Box: 5
    - A Certain Kind of Hum, Fishelman, Ben (Box 5)
    - A Leap of Faith, Crandall, Jason (Box 5)
    - A Queen's Symphony, Mercurio, Stephanie (Box 5)
    - Ashes to Ashes, Rescoria, Kim (Box 5)
    - Assumptions, Jannicelli, Jessica (Box 5)
    - Battles You Can't Win, Rescoria, Kim (Box 5)
    - Convulsing Twins, Cahill, Bryon (Box 5)
    - Decisions, Decisions, Treacy, Katie (Box 5)
    - Famous Men: An Act Mizzling, Feurstein, Michael James (Box 5)
    - In Brother I Trust, Heineman, Alex (Box 5)
    - None So Blind, Mewhiney, Kevin (Box 5)
    - The Borders of Arcadia, Thompson, Scott R. (Box 5)
    - The Engagement, Lynch, Heather (Box 5)
    - The First Letter to Sabrina, Thompson, Scott R. (Box 5)
    - Tuesday, Cahill, Bryon (Box 5)
    - Whatever Happened to Long Island Mike???, Curry, Daniel (Box 5)
  - Subseries 1.16: A Touch of Harry: A Collection of Plays Commemorating the Nineteenth Anniversary of Marist College's Annual Festival of Short Plays by Students - 1999, 1.16; Box: 5
    - The Pale Eggs of the Beast, Cahill, Bryon (Box 5)
    - Pickles, Coppola, Giovanna (Box 5)
    - The Wake, D'amore, Patrick (Box 5)
    - Mama's Boy, Hecht, Ben (Box 5)
    - Freshman Year of Life, Heineman, Alex (Box 5)
    - $$$ Lucrative, Ketcham, Brian (Box 5)
    - The Heart Remembers, Lorenz, Dawn (Box 5)
    - The Journey, Mason, Keisha (Box 5)
    - Portrait of a Murder, McEvily, Pete (Box 5)
    - Love Thyself, Reeves, Ivy (Box 5)
    - The Devil and Mike Faust or Satan Goes to College, Sullivan, John (Box 5)
    - A Quiet Sabbath in Amherst, Thompson, S. Randall (Box 5)
  - Subseries 1.17: Early Light: New Plays For a New Century - 2000, 1.17; Box: 5
    - A Night in the Park, Orgera, Dean (Box 5)
    - The Restless Nights of Roxy Thrill, Sullivan, John (Box 5)
    - The Paper War, Hecht, Ben I. (Box 5)
    - Power Lunch, Tyburski, Daniel (Box 5)
    - Ridiculous, Clemens, Chris (Box 5)
    - Act IV of Richard Once and Future King of England, Thompson, S. Randall (Box 5)
    - Gramma's Treasure Chest, Napoli, Shelly L. (Box 5)
    - South of Sunrise, Genesi, Kimberly S. (Box 5)
    - Elbow Room, Moorman, Sam (Box 5)
  - Subseries 1.18: Swift As A Shadow: A Collection of New Short Plays, 2001; 1.18; Box: 6
    - Ange Coeur, Clemens, Chris (Box 6)
    - Angel Down, Hecht, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - Closure, Garcia, George Luis Jr. (Box 6)
    - Dinner With Cactus, Smith, Jeremy D. (Box 6)
    - Is Ignorance Bliss: An Exploration of Ebeneezer Pudd, Musorrafiti, Lori (Box 6)
    - Jono's Big Party, Breslin, Dennis (Box 6)
    - That Girl, Flynn, Matthew (Box 6)
    - The Choice, Irizarry, Grace (Box 6)
    - Three's A Crowd, Montemurro, Lauren A. (Box 6)
    - Till We Meet Again, LeBoeuf, Jennifer (Box 6)
    - What About Birds, Nigrelli, Gianluca (Box 6)
  - Subseries 1.19: True Beginnings: Student Written Plays, 2002; 1.19; Box: 6
    - Toppings, Flynn, Matthew (Box 6)
    - Life as a Movie, Suesens, Michelle (Box 6)
    - La Dame du Chevalier, Pause, Stephen (Box 6)
    - Pointless Conversation, Nigro, Nick (Box 6)
    - Passing Through Boredom, That, Cynthia (Box 6)
    - Rocketman, Wentlejewski, Joseph (Box 6)
    - The Kiosk, Gemme, Michael (Box 6)
    - Sex and Pepsi, Weber, Chris (Box 6)
  - Subseries 1.20: Caviar to the General: A Collection of Plays by Student Playwrights, 2003; 1.20; Box: 7
    - My Jesus Stopped, D'Angelo, Gina (Box 7)
    - Bringing Home Jimmy Stewart, Gareau, Karla (Box 7)
    - I Spy Love, Gemme, Michael (Box 7)
    - The Man from Korvutunturi, Gemme, Michael (Box 7)
    - Thirteen Dollars for Therapy, Gross, Landan (Box 7)
    - Nunc Scio Quid Sit Amor, Kasche, Edward J. (Box 7)
    - Slippery Fingers, Kaylor, Brooke (Box 7)
    - A Side Order of Sacrilege, McGrath, Jim (Box 7)
    - Fun and Games, Messina, Anthony (Box 7)
    - 1-900-GET-GIRL, Weber, Chris (Box 7)
- 2. Student Plays, 2; Boxes: 8 - 15
  Alphabetically by Title
  - $$$ Lucrative, Ketchman, Brian (Box 8)
  - 21 Park Place, McCann, Christina (Box 8)
  - Abandoned Treasures, Bakke, John (Box 8)
  - After After Land, Giaquinto, Matt& Gretzinger, Jerry (Box 8)
  - After All, Bakke, John (Box 8)
  - All the Candidate's Men, Marble, Mark (Box 8)
  - All the Dips are Dancing, Scully, Erin (Box 8)
  - Ange Coeur, Clemens, Chris (Box 8)
  - Angel Down, Hecht, Benjamin (Box 8)
  - Apple and the Tree, The, Fahey, Jeanne (Box 8)
  - Armageddon vs. Joe Shmoe, Cahill, Bryon (Box 8)
  - Assume Nothing, Caracciolo, Daniel Lawrence (Box 8)
  - Assumptions, Jannicelli, Jessica (Box 8)
  - B.S. Formula, The, Anderson, Jerome D. (Box 8)
  - Backstage, Miller, Mark (Box 8)
  - Beginnings, Lantos, Teresa Ann (Box 8)
  - Black Coming Light, Kennedy, Loretta A. (Box 8)
  - Blackout, Giaquinto, Matthew (Box 8)
  - Bonds of Obedience, The, Smyle, Alex (Box 8)
  - Cars, Lecky, John (Box 8)
  - Choice, The, Lrizarry, Grace (Box 8)
  - Choice's, Hesselton, Clair R. (Box 8)
  - Chop Suey, Roche, John (Box 9)
  - Clancy Street, Milbihill, Michael (Box 9)
  - "Closure" Sometimes... it's all you need, Garcia, George Louis Jr. (Box 9)
  - College Years, The, Mayone, Joan (Box 9)
  - Complications, O'Connor, Kerin (Box 9)
  - Constructive Criticism, Anderson, John P. (Box 9)
  - Courtmartial of James T. Kirk, The, Eastwood, Steve (Box 9)
  - Dear Ann, O'Brian, Joseph (Box 9)
  - Death Meets the Lovebug, Higgins, Bob (Box 9)
  - Decisions, Decisions, Treacy, Katie (Box 9)
  - Deli, Morman, Samuel (Box 9)
  - Devil and Mike Faust, The or Satan Goes to College, Sullivan,James (Box 9)
  - Dinner for Three, Lawless, Christina (Box 9)
  - Dinner with Cactus, Smith, Jeremy D. (Box 9)
  - Down to the Wire, Penny, George R. (Box 9)
  - Downward Spiral, The, Schilling, Mark (Box 9)
  - Drugs, Sex, Rock& Roll, Bakke, John (Box 9)
  - Elevator Music (Box 10)
  - Engagement, The (Box 10)
  - Engine's Heat (Box 10)
  - Epiphany (Box 10)
  - Farewell Tour (Box 10)
  - Father's Day (Box 10)
  - Favorite, The (Box 10)
  - Feet (Box 10)
  - Forgiveness (Box 10)
  - Freshman Year of Life (Box 10)
  - From the Porch (Box 10)
  - Game, The (Box 10)
  - Gate Keeper, The (Box 10)
  - Gifted (Box 10)
  - Got Me Wrong (Box 10)
  - Have A Good Life (Box 10)
  - Heart Remembers, The (Box 10)
  - Icing on the Wedding Cake, Heineman, Alex (Box 11)
  - In A Lonely Place, Larkin, Michael G. (Box 11)
  - Insecurities, Van Vlack, Ken (Box 11)
  - Is Ignorance Bliss: An Exploration of Ebeneezer Pudd, Musorrafiti, Lori (Box 11)
  - Jono's Big Party, Breslin, Dennis (Box 11)
  - Journey, The, Mason, Keisha (Box 11)
  - Jury Room, The, Kusa, Deborah (Box 11)
  - Just Us, Blakke, John (Box 11)
  - Katy, Kieran, Alex (Box 11)
  - Last Supper, The, Ricci, Royal D. (Box 11)
  - Late Ending, O'Connor, Brian (Box 11)
  - Leap of Faith, A, Blake, John (Box 11)
  - Legend Has It, Landry, Karen (Box 11)
  - Life's Eyes, Roche, John (Box 11)
  - Love Thyself, Reeves, Ivy (Box 11)
  - Mama's Boy, Hecht, Ben I. (Box 11)
  - Man in a Chair, a Woman at the Window, A, Crandall, Jason (Box 12)
  - Marcie and Her Imagination, Crary, Kami (Box 12)
  - Martin Cohan, Flynn, Matthew (Box 12)
  - Me and Brian, Sousa, AnnMichelle (Box 12)
  - Milestones, Roche, John (Box 12)
  - Moment of Silence, A, unknown (Box 12)
  - Money to Burn, Anderson, John (Box 12)
  - Moonlight at Nightfall, Bakke, John (Box 12)
  - Mortimer Bites the Big Apple (The Mort Strikes Back), Murray, Jon& Lenhart, Paul (Box 12)
  - My Brother's Keeper, O'Hare, James (Box 12)
  - Nihl, McNamara, Shannon (Box 12)
  - Observation Post Alpha, Smyle, Alex (Box 12)
  - Of Brass Rings and Finer Things, Gallagher, Thomas P. (Box 12)
  - Of Wise Owls and Human Mischief: Scenes from a Romance, Marafioti, Pat (Box 12)
  - Pale Eggs of the Beast, The, Cahill, Bryon (Box 12)
  - Party Life, The, Fredsall, Peter (Box 12)
  - Paths of Progress, The, Eyck, David Ten (Box 12)
  - Payment of Dues, Brunner, Susan& Crecca, Andrew (Box 12)
  - Pickles, Coppola, Giovanna (Box 12)
  - Piece of Mind, Glaze, Anndalena (Box 12)
  - Portrait of a Murder, McEvily, Pete (Box 13)
  - Premonition, Freydl, Jeff E. (Box 13)
  - Quiet Sunday in Amherst, A, Fishelmen, Ben (Box 13)
  - Resale T's, The, Anderson, Donald (Box 13)
  - Romeo and Julio, unknown (Box 13)
  - Romeo, Romeo, Zizzi, Sara (Box 13)
  - Saints or Sinners, Fitzpatrick, Diane& Eustace, Don (Box 13)
  - Second Sight, Larkin, Michael (Box 13)
  - Seen But Not Heard, Serafini, Chris (Box 13)
  - Shooting the Cowboys, Curry, Daniel P. (Box 13)
  - Sisters, Magdalen, Karyn (Box 13)
  - Skeletons in the Closet, Cunney, Don (Box 13)
  - Sketches, Weston, Leslie (Box 13)
  - Smoking Car, The, Creighton, Sean (Box 13)
  - Stranger than Fiction, Liepis, Marc (Box 13)
  - Summer Employment, MacGowan, Carl (Box 14)
  - Take it Easy, Soldier, DeFelice, James (Box 14)
  - Taking it to the Streets, Adamski, Meg (Box 14)
  - Tangled Web, A, Thompson, Scott R. (Box 14)
  - That Girl, Flyn, Matthew (Box 14)
  - Thicker than Water, McBride, Jon (Box 14)
  - Three's a Crowd, Montemurrow, Lauren (Box 14)
  - Till We Meet Again, LeBoeuf, Jennifer (Box 14)
  - To Be Remembered, Sabol, Richard (Box 14)
  - To Fit the Cloth, Pomilla, Diane (Box 14)
  - Truth of the Matter, The, Begley, Vincent (Box 14)
  - Turning Tables, Ivanoff, Donald N. Jr. (Box 14)
  - Tumbleweeds, Mulvihill, Michael (Box 14)
  - Twin Billing, Disana, Gina (Box 14)
  - Two Bit, Anderson, J. Patrick (Box 14)
  - Unsung Hero, The (The Comic Tragedy), Speers, Mike (Box 15)
  - Unsuspecting Customers, Dwyer, Kevin (Box 15)
  - Upstage, Sousa, Shelly (Box 15)
  - Vows, Wing, Terrence (Box 15)
  - Wake, The, D'amore, Patrick (Box 15)
  - Wedding Bliss, Hubbs, Michele (Box 15)
  - What About Birds, Nigrelli, Gianluca (Box 15)
  - What are Friends For?, O'Donnell, Rick& Magdalen, Karyn (Box 15)
  - What Ever Happened to Long Island Mike?, Curry, Daniel (Box 15)
  - Witness, The, McCann, Christina (Box 15)
  - Wonderworld, Stepmoroski, Tara (Box 15)
- 3. Videos, 3; Boxes: 16 - 22
  - Alan Arkin (2 tapes) (Box 16)
  - All in the Timing (Box 16)
  - Anything Goes (Box 16)
  - Beautiful Thing (Box 16)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof 3/7/99 (Box 16)
  - Dancing in the End Zone (Box 16)
  - Dancing at Lughnasa and Stone Soup (Box 16)
  - Dean Cox Tapes (2) (Box 16)
  - A Doll's House 3/6/97 (Box 16)
  - The Emperors New Clothes 4/9/97 (Box 16)
  - Eng, 2 + 1 Plays, 12/6/96 (Box 17)
  - ETG 2 + 1 Pays, 12/16/96 (Box 17)
  - ETG Double Bill, 12/7/95 (Box 17)
  - Evening of One Acts (Box 17)
  - Experimental Theatre, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Experimental Theatre for Dean Cox (Box 17)
  - Festival of Plays, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Festival of Plays, Spring 1995, Tapes 1& 2 (Box 17)
  - Festival 1995& Dance Club Pantomime (Fall '95) Hey Big Spender (Box 17)
  - Festival 1996, Tapes 1& 2 (Box 17)
  - Festival 1997 (Box 18)
  - Festival 2000 (Box 18)
  - Fiddler on the Roof Tapes 1& 2, 11/17 - 11/18/95 (Box 18)
  - Fiddler on the Roof (one tape) (Box 18)
  - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Forum 11/20/93 (Box 18)
  - The Glass Slipper 4/12/94 (Box 18)
  - Guys and Dolls Tapes 1& 2, 11/21/96 (Box 18)
  - Humorists, 4/11/95 (Box 18)
  - I Hate Hamlet (2 tapes) 10/30/94 (Box 19)
  - The Importance of Being Ernest 10/15/00 (Box 19)
  - Into the Woods (Box 19)
  - Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat (2 tapes) 11/20/97 (Box 19)
  - Lend Me a Tenor 10/15/93 (Box 19)
  - Lessons and Carols, 12/14/96 (Box 19)
  - Love Letters May 1995 (Box 19)
  - Love, Sex, and the IRS 10/15/95 (Box 19)
  - Machinal Fall 1997 (Box 19)
  - Marvin's Room 2/27/97 (Box 19)
  - Me and My Girl (2 tapes) 11/20/94 (Box 20)
  - Moon Over Buffalo 10/9/97 (Box 20)
  - The Mousetrap (2 tapes) 3/2/96 (Box 20)
  - Noises Off (2 tapes) 2/3-5/95 (Box 20)
  - One Acts, 12/5/98 (Box 20)
  - Prelude to a Kiss 2/10/96 (Box 20)
  - Present Laughter (2 tapes) 10/11/98 (Box 20)
  - Robin Hood (Camera Two) (Box 20)
  - Robin Hood (Camera Two) (Box 21)
  - Rumors 10/11/96 (Box 21)
  - Rumplestiltskin (2 tapes) 3/31/96 (Box 21)
  - Six Characters in Search of an Author 2/14/96 (Box 21)
  - Stone Soup 3/29/98 (Box 21)
  - A Streecar Named Desire (Box 21)
  - Talk Radio (Box 21)
  - Taming of the Shrew 4/7 - 4/9/? (Box 21)
  - To Fit the Cloth (Box 21)
  - Tom Foolery (Box 21)
  - Triple Bill, MCCTA, Identity Crisis, The Room,& Actors Nightmare 2/17/94 (Box 22)
  - Vagina Monologues (Box 22)
  - The Vagina Monologues 2/14/99 (Box 22)
  - A View From the Bridge 2/12/00 (Box 22)
  - West Side Story 11/21/98 (Box 22)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf? (2 tapes) (Box 22)
  - World Goes Round 3/8/00 (Box 22)